Guide to the Lefferts family papers ARC.145
Brooklyn Historical Society
- Series 8: Books and Scrapbooks, 1659-1917; 3868; 8 Linear Feet in 2 record cartons, 2 document boxes, and 4 oversized boxes.
  - Catechizatie Ober den Heidelberghischen Catechismus der Gereformeerde Christelicke Religie by Petrum DeWitte, 1663; 4200 (Box 6, Item 5)
  - Cookbook (probably of Maria Lott Lefferts), 1800s; 4199 (Box 6, Item 6)
  - Genealogy of the Lefferts family, 1650-1718 by Teunis G. Bergen, 1862, 1878; 4191 (Box 6, Item 7)
    Includes a write up on and letter to James Edward Jenkins from Commodore Grinnell and portrait photos of Cornelia Lefferts (Mrs. James Edward Jenkins), James Edward Jenkins, Lewis Lefferts Jenkins, and Georgette Pell (Mrs. Lewis Lefferts Jenkins)
  - Het Nieuwe Testament (inscribed with "Pieter De Marest"), 1717, 1728-1748; 4188 (Box 6, Item 8)
    Includes birth and death lists for Demarest family.
  - Het Nieuwe Testament (inscribed with "AV"), 1758; 4187 (Box 6, Item 9)
  - Het Nieuwe Testament (inscribed with "Femmetie Hegemann"), 1770, 1775; 4186 (Box 6, Item 10)
  - "History of the Town of Flatbush" by Rev. Robert G. Strong reprinted from The Illustrated History of Kings County, editor Dr. H. R. Stiles, 1884; 4208 (Box 6, Item 11)
    Moved to Mold Box 1: Two extra copies.
  - Housekeeping in old Virginia: Containing contributions from two hundred and fifty ladies in Virginia, Ed. Marion Cabell Tyree (pages missing), 1879; 4209 (Box 6, Item 12)
  - The Hymnal, music book, 1894; 4206 (Box Mold 1, Item 2)
  - A Large Dictionary English and Dutch, in Two Parts, 4th Edition (inscribed with: Mrs. G.L. Martense), 1749; 4210 (Box 7, Item 1)
  - Laws of the State of New York passed at the Third Meeting of the Ninth Session of the Legislature of the said State (inscribed with "Philip Nagel"), 1786, 1917; 4195 (Box 7, Item 2)
    Includes letter from letter from New York State Supreme Court Justice Russell Benedict to Lefferts Historical House explaining Philip Nagel's connection to Flatbush history.
  - Lefferts Bible: Dutch Bible, 1637; 4211 (Box 8, Item 1)
  - Lefferts Bible: Dutch Bible (of Cowenhoven family and Lefferts family), 1741; 4212 (Box 8, Item 2)
  - Lefferts Bible: Dutch Bible (of Femmetie Lefferts and Lefferts Cooke family), 1741; 4213 (Box 9, Item 1)
  - Lefferts Bible: Universal Family Bible by Rev. Benjamin Kennicott, 1793; 4214 (Box 9, Item 2)
  - The London Art of Cookery and Domestic Housekeepers' Complete Assistant by John Farley, 1783; 4190 (Box 10, Item 1)
  - Lust-Hof der Christelijker Gebeden by Willem Teellinck, 1672, 1743; 4185 (Box 10, Item 2)
  - On the Chafing-Dish, cookbook, 1890; 4204 (Box Mold 1, Item 3)
  - Receipts donated by the members of Saint Anna's Chapter of Saint Paul's Church in the Village of Flatbush, 1909; 4193 (Box 10, Item 3)
  - Redelijke Godsdienst by Wilhelmus a Brakel (inscribed with "Cornelius Van Der Veer"), 1739, 1788; 4196 (Box 10, Item 4)
  - Scrapbook of Carrie Alexander, circa 1884; 4207 (Box Mold 1, Item 4)
  - Scrapbook of George William Alexander, circa 1860s-1890s; 4279 (Box 11, Item 1)
  - The Waverly Gallery by Charles Heath (inscribed with "Gertrude Lefferts Vanderbilt"), 1841; 4205 (Box Mold 1, Item 5)
  - De Weegschale der genade Gods by Bernardus Freeman (pages missing), circa 1721; 4276 (Box 12, Item 1)
  - The Works of that late learned minister of God's Holy word, Mr. William Pemble (4th Edition), 1659; 4281 (Box 12, Item 2)
  - Lefferts Bible: Holy Bible (of Carrie Ann Lefferts), 1743; 4278 (Box 12, Item 3)